### OPERATIONS/HR MANAGER

### Summary

Human Resources Manager who promotes a team-oriented and open-door environment that is conducive to a successful staff. Offering 7 years of experience and knowledge in training, orientation and incentive program creation. I am an expert communicator and negotiator with strong conflict resolution skills. Extensive background in recruitment and retention and records management. Comfortable with taking the lead in employment protocol compliance and in anticipating staffing needs.

## Highlights

- Staffing and recruiting professional
- Interviewing expertise
- Benefits administrator
- Employee relations
- Manager coaching and training
- HRIS applications proficient
- Payroll expertise

#### Skills

general accounting, attention to detail, budgeting, coaching, excellent communication, conferences, cost control, resolve customer complaints, customer service, directing associates, financial, focus, hIring, human resources, Inventory Control, Kronos, leadership, team development, office equipment, Oracle, payroll, Peoplesoff, presentations profit and loss, purchasing, receiving, recruitment, repairs, safety (OSHA / Hazmat), sales, scheduling, staffing, management, strategic, supervisory skills, team player, training programs

### Experience

## Operations/HR Manager

May 2013 to August 2015 Aimbridge Hospitality il/4 Morristown, NJ

- Conducted benefits administration for benefit-eligible employees.
- Addressed inquires from employees and management regarding new-hire activity and ongoing employee relation issues.
- Facilitated monthly meetings to develop strategies that would positively influence workplace relationships.
- Recruited and interviewed 5 applicants per month.
- Answered employee questions regarding HR and Payroll and resolved any issues.
- Conducted new employee orientation to foster positive attitude toward organizational objectives.
- Directed personnel, training activities.
- Identified staff vacancies and recruited, interviewed and selected applicants.
- Accurately processed data, validation and transmission for weekly, semi-monthly and sales payrolls.
- Managed payroll and time and attendance systems.
- Enforced established payroll-related policies, procedures and regulations and adherence to company and governmental policies.
- · Responded to employee inquiries regarding payroll and timekeeping.
- Onboarded new employees in the time reporting and payroll systems.
- Compiled financial, accounting and auditing reports and tables for cash receipts, expenditures, accounts payable, receivables and profits and losses.
- Worked quickly and efficiently, with minimal oversight, to accomplish assigned duties.
- Verified that information in the computer system was up-to-date and accurate.
- Processed confidential tax form information.
- Developed and created a more effective filing system to accelerate paperwork processing.
- Assisted with payroll preparation and entered data into cumulative payroll document.

## Operations/HR Manager

May 2008 to May 2013 Aimbridge Hospitality il/4 Petaluma, CA

- Conducted benefits administration for benefit-eligible employees.
- Addressed inquires from employees and management regarding new-hire activity and ongoing employee relation issues.
- Facilitated monthly meetings to develop strategies that would positively influence workplace relationships.
- Recruited and interviewed 5 applicants per month.
- Answered employee questions regarding HR and Payroll and resolved any issues.
- Conducted new employee orientation to foster positive attitude toward organizational objectives.
- Directed personnel, training activities.
- Identified staff vacancies and recruited, interviewed and selected applicants.
- Accurately processed data, validation and transmission for weekly, semi-monthly and sales payrolls.
- Managed payroll and time and attendance systems.
- Enforced established payroll-related policies, procedures and regulations and adherence to company and governmental policies.
- Responded to employee inquiries regarding payroll and timekeeping.
- Onboarded new employees in the time reporting and payroll systems.
- Compiled financial, accounting and auditing reports and tables for cash receipts, expenditures, accounts payable, receivables and profits and losses.
- Worked quickly and efficiently, with minimal oversight, to accomplish assigned duties.
- Verified that information in the computer system was up-to-date and accurate.

- Processed confidential tax form information.
- Developed and created a more effective filing system to accelerate paperwork processing.
- Assisted with payroll preparation and entered data into cumulative payroll document.
- Addressed negative customer feedback immediately.
- Provided a high level of product and leadership support to representatives and clients.
- Routinely prepared and evaluated CRM reports to identify problems and areas for improvement.
- Effectively communicated with team members to maintain clearly defined expectations.
- Effectively managed departmental expenses to stay within allocated budget.
- Resolved customer questions, issues and complaints.
- Developed rapport with the customer base by handling difficult issues with professionalism

# Receiving Inventory Control Manager

October 1994 to March 2008 BJ Wholesale Club i1/4 City, STATE

- Resolved customer complaints by exchanging merchandise, refunding money and adjusting bills.
- Shared product knowledge with customers while making personal recommendations.
- Maintained friendly and professional customer interactions.
- Processed an average of 50 invoices per day for a large-scale organization.
- Conducted month-end balance sheet reviews and reconciled any variances.
- Researched and resolved billing and invoice problems.
- Managed accounting operations, accounting close, account reporting and reconciliations.
- Planned and executed operational audits of various business areas using risk-based audit methodology.
- Maintained detailed administrative and procedural processes to improve accuracy and efficiency.
- Verified and logged in deadlines for responding to daily inquiries.
- Prevented store losses using awareness, attention to detail and integrity.
- Organized weekly sales reports for the sales department to track product success.
- Generated sales and inventory reports in Excel with data from a variety of sources, maintaining a 100% accuracy rate.
- Directed personnel, training and labor relations activities.
- Served as a link between management and employees by handling questions, interpreting and administering contracts and helping resolve work-related problems.
- Explained human resources policies and procedures to all employees.
- Helped training and development staff with all aspects of training coordination.
- Resolved personnel issues regarding human resources matters needing clarification, submissions and corrections.

### Education

Bachelor of Science : Computer Science Franklin Pierce College  $i\frac{1}{4}$  City , State

Associate of Arts: Liberal Arts Mount Ida College i1/4 City, State

Liberal Arts